Dee Mackinnon

Clinical Reimbursement Specialist - RAC-C

Cohasset, MA 02025 deemackinnon6_iby@indeedemail.com 508-245-1893

I have been a management nurse since 2004 in my role as a clinical reimbursement specialist. My position involved supervisory experience as well in long term care.

I have worked in facilities with 60 to 130 patients often being the manager on duty and responsible for the entire facility.

I have also worked at assisted living facilities, namely, The Village at Willow Crossing in Mansfield, The Pond Home in Wrentham, Doolittle Home in Foxboro, Aegis of Issaquah and Peter's Creek in Redmond WA.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

MDS Coordinator

Harborview Centre Cohasset - Cohasset, MA March 2018 to Present

I am the MDS and MMQ Coordinator and Case Manager at Harborview Center. The facility is closing so I am looking for another position.

MDS Coordinator

Harborlights - South Boston, MA November 2017 to March 2018

MDS/PPS Coordinator in building with 90 resident's. Facility closed its doors at the end of February 2018.

Wellness Nurse

Covenant Shores Retirement Community - Mercer Island, WA November 2016 to November 2017

Assisted living community with a nursing home for the resident's who lived in the community.

MDS/PPS Coordinator

Paqramount Rehab - Seattle, WA September 2016 to October 2017

Was able to keep facility from closing by the State by bringing multiple MDS's current. State auditor told me that it was because of my work that they were allowing the facility to stay open. I was the only MDS/PPS Coordinator in the facility, I increased reimbursement, worked on case mix, got physician certs done, was responsible for Medicare meetings, NOMNC's, care plans, setting ARD's, interviewing patients, everything reimbursement based.

Wellness Nurse

Aegis Living - Issaquah, WA January 2016 to October 2016

Wellness supervisor every weekend.

MDS/PPS Coordinator

Covenant Shores - Mercer Island, WA August 2015 to October 2016

All MDS/PPS coordinator responsibilities.

Wellness Nurse

Peters Creek Retirement - Redmond, WA February 2016 to September 2016

I was the weekend Wellness Supervisor at Peter's Creek and also at Aegis of Issaquah WA.

MDS Coordinator

Norwell Knoll 2010 to 2014

which was purchased by Royal.

Clinical Reimbursement Specialist

RAC-C

2017

As an MDS Coordinator I am able to ensure timely, accurate and complete assessments of residents health and functional status during their entire stay at facilities and assessment periods. I participate in the pre-admission process to ensure essential information that is needed for MDS/Case Mix optimization is obtained from referral sources. I ensure accurate and timely completion of all Medicare required documents in order to assure appropriate reimbursement of services provided to residents within a facility. I work in collaboration with the Director of Rehab to ensure the most appropriate assessment reference date (ARD) is utilized for Medicare/Managed care assessments.. I track Medicare residents to determine continued and appropriate Medicare eligibility and benefit period through regular communication with the Business Office Manager. I ensure that additional requirements of the Medicare program are met such as physician certification and recertification and NOMNC letters are met. I perform continuous MDS reviews to assure appropriate RUG categories are achieved through the capture of appropriate clinical documentation, identify opportunities to maximize reimbursement by monitoring and auditing documentation and educating staff on documentation techniques to code the level of care they are delivering. I schedule all MDS's, OBRA, all Medicare A MDS's, COT, SOT, EOT's. I host Medicare and PPS meetings. I schedule and host care plan meetings in accordance with ARD's. I use a PPS Calculator for all Medicare A patients tracking. I open all the MDS Assessments and with new admissions open the admission care plans.

Current: Harborview SNF in Cohasset MA., I am the only MDS/MMQ, Case Manager in the facility.

Education

Bachelor's in Psychology

University of Waterloo Ontario - Waterloo, ON

Skills

- PCC/MATRIX/VISION (10+ years)
- Skilled Nursing (10+ years)
- Nursing Home (10+ years)
- Assessment (10+ years)
- RN

Certifications and Licenses

LPN

July 2017 to July 2019

LPN

LPN, AANAC.

Additional Information

AANAC Certified